Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have another episode in our series about small talk.
我是Catherine，今天我们带来另一集关于闲聊的系列节目。
So small talk Marco is what exactly?
那么Marco，闲聊到底是什么？
Quick little conversation that you have maybe with a colleague or friend or even with a
就是你和同事、朋友，甚至是在电梯里遇到的
stranger maybe in the elevator.
陌生人进行的简短对话。
Just about the weather or some small little topic.
只聊天气或一些琐碎的小话题。
So you're not talking about the meaning of life.
所以你不会谈论人生的意义。
You're talking about the weather or food.
而是聊天气或食物。
So let's check out today's dialogue and we'll be back in a minute to talk more about what's
那么让我们看看今天的对话，稍后我们会回来
going on.
详细讨论内容。
Oh dear miss, you are soaked.
哎呀，小姐，你全身都湿透了。
Wow, it's really raining heavily outside.
哇，外面雨下得真大。
Yes, it sure is.
是啊，确实如此。
I had to run here from work.
我不得不从工作的地方跑过来。
I need to rush as I'm on my lunch break.
我得赶紧，因为我在午休时间。
Well please, why don't you go ahead of me in line.
那请吧，不如你排在我前面。
I'm in no hurry.
我不着急。
Oh, that's so nice of you.
哦，你真是太好了。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
My pleasure miss.
不客气，小姐。
Actually, could you recommend what to eat here?
其实，你能推荐这里有什么好吃的吗？
I've never been here before.
我以前从没来过这里。
Sure.
当然可以。
Well, the avocado sandwich is delicious and it's the healthiest thing on the menu.
嗯，牛油果三明治很好吃，而且是菜单上最健康的。
Personally, I think the beef salad is the tastiest choice.
我个人觉得牛肉沙拉是最美味的选择。
I usually get that.
我通常点那个。
Also, the milkshakes are the best milkshakes in town.
还有，这里的奶昔是镇上最好喝的。
Well, thanks for the suggestions.
嗯，谢谢你的建议。
No, don't mention it.
不客气。
Alright we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So, as we saw in this dialogue, it's a small talk conversation with two strangers who are
所以，正如我们在对话中看到的，这是一次两个陌生人的闲聊，
actually buying some food.
他们实际上是在买食物。
So this is something that could happen if you are waiting in line at a supermarket,
这种情况可能发生在你排队等超市结账时，
if you're at the bank or even at a shop like in this case.
在银行，或者像这次一样在商店里。
Exactly.
没错。
This kind of conversation happens all the time.
这种对话经常发生。
So let's take a look at some words and phrases in today's language takeaway.
那么让我们看看今天语言要点中的一些单词和短语。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
Alright so the first word that we have for you today is the gentleman, the older person,
好的，今天我们第一个词是那位绅士，那位年长的人，
noticed how wet the girl was.
注意到女孩有多湿。
She said you are soaked.
她说你湿透了。
Alright so it's raining outside and he says oh dear miss, you are soaked.
好的，外面在下雨，他说哎呀，小姐，你湿透了。
Alright this is an adjective.
好的，这是一个形容词。
It describes what she looks like.
它描述她的样子。
So if you are soaked, it means that you are a little bit wet?
所以如果你湿透了，意思是有点湿？
Very wet.
非常湿。
You know you can say that someone is a little wet but if they're soaked, it means their
你知道你可以说某人有点湿，但如果他们湿透了，意思是他们的
shoes, their pants, their shirt, their hat, everything is very wet.
鞋子、裤子、衬衫、帽子，所有东西都非常湿。
Okay, you are soaked.
好的，你湿透了。
And so it's an adjective even though it has an ed ending, it may look like a verb or in
所以它是一个形容词，尽管它有ed结尾，可能看起来像动词或
the past but it's not.
过去式，但并不是。
It's an adjective with an ed ending.
它是一个以ed结尾的形容词。
That's right.
没错。
So it's raining outside, this woman is very wet, she's soaked, she's wet and she says
所以外面在下雨，这个女人非常湿，她湿透了，她湿了，她说
I have to rush, I have to hurry because of what?
我得赶紧，我得快点，因为什么？
Because I'm on my lunch break.
因为我在午休。
She's on her lunch break.
她在午休。
Okay so during work, we might have something called a break.
好的，所以在工作期间，我们可能有所谓的休息时间。
This is a short time when we don't have to work.
这是一段不用工作的短时间。
Five minutes, ten minutes.
五分钟、十分钟。
And the break that we have at lunch when we get to eat is a little bit longer.
而午餐时我们吃饭的休息时间稍长一些。
So we call this a lunch break.
所以我们称之为午休。
That's right.
没错。
So usually people have their lunch break let's say at noon or one o'clock and it's usually
所以通常人们在中午或一点钟有午休，而且通常
an hour like you say.
像你说的，是一个小时。
That's right, an hour.
没错，一个小时。
Okay so she's on her lunch break and that's why she's in a hurry and so the other guy
好的，所以她在午休，这就是为什么她很匆忙，于是另一个人
let her go in front of him and he asked her for some suggestions.
让她排在自己前面，然后他向她征求一些建议。
What is good here?
这里什么好吃？
What do you recommend to eat?
你推荐吃什么？
That's right.
没错。
So he's not familiar with the food but the woman is and she says well, the avocado sandwich
所以他对食物不熟悉，但那个女人熟悉，她说，嗯，牛油果三明治
is delicious.
很好吃。
Now let's talk about this fruit because it is a fruit, right Marco?
现在我们来谈谈这种水果，因为它是一种水果，对吧Marco？
It's a fruit, an avocado.
它是一种水果，牛油果。
You see this, it looks like a big green pear more or less.
你看这个，它看起来差不多像一个大的绿色梨。
That's right.
没错。
Well it's green on the inside and it's dark on the outside.
嗯，里面是绿色的，外面是深色的。
So to eat it, you have to take off the skin.
所以吃它的时候，你得把皮剥掉。
Yeah, that's right.
对，没错。
And inside it's kind of buttery almost.
而且里面几乎有种黄油般的口感。
It's not hard like a banana or an apple.
它不像香蕉或苹果那样硬。
It's kind of more very, very soft.
它更偏向于非常非常软。
You can take it out with a spoon.
你可以用勺子把它挖出来。
That's right.
没错。
It's very, very delicious and it's very common in a lot of Latin cooking where you have for
它非常非常美味，而且在很多拉丁烹饪中很常见，比如
example guacamole in Mexican cooking which is made primarily of avocados.
墨西哥烹饪中的鳄梨酱，主要就是用鳄梨做的。
That's right.
没错。
So she recommends the avocado sandwich and then she goes on to describe some of the food
所以她推荐了鳄梨三明治，然后她继续描述了一些食物，
and now here, we're going to take a look at some adjectives but in a superlative form.
现在这里，我们要看看一些形容词的最高级形式。
For example, she said it's the healthiest thing on the menu, this sandwich.
比如，她说这个三明治是菜单上最健康的食物。
Okay, so this is a really important point Marco and I'm glad you brought it up.
好的，马可，这真是个重点，我很高兴你提出来。
I can say that this food is healthy.
我可以说这个食物很健康。
That means it's good for my body.
意思是它对身体好。
But if I say that it's the healthiest, what does that mean?
但如果我说它是最健康的，那是什么意思？
How is that different from healthy?
这和健康有什么不同？
Usually you're saying that it's on the list of things that are at the restaurant maybe
通常你是在说，在餐厅的菜单上，它可能是
that are healthy.
健康食物中的一种。
This is the most healthy.
这是最健康的。
But you don't say most healthy.
但你不说“最健康”（most healthy）。
You say healthiest.
你说“healthiest”。
Healthiest, okay.
“Healthiest”，好的。
So is chocolate cake the healthiest thing on the menu?
那么巧克力蛋糕是菜单上最健康的食物吗？
No, probably not.
不，可能不是。
It's probably the least healthy.
它可能是最不健康的。
So on top we have the healthiest thing on the menu.
所以最上面我们有菜单上最健康的食物。
We also have another superlative.
我们还有另一个最高级。
We heard the word tastiest.
我们听到了“tastiest”这个词。
Right.
对。
This comes from the adjective tasty.
这来自形容词“tasty”。
Something is delicious.
某样东西很美味。
It's tasty.
它很好吃。
It's good.
它很好。
But here we're saying that it's the thing that tastes the best, the tastiest choice.
但这里我们说的是味道最好的东西，最好吃的选择。
Okay, so I think that the avocado sandwich is the tastiest.
好的，所以我觉得鳄梨三明治是最好吃的。
That means I think it's the best thing you can eat.
意思是我觉得这是你能吃到的最好的东西。
And that's another one actually.
实际上还有另一个。
Best is another superlative but it's a little bit different because it's not an is, is,
“Best”是另一个最高级，但有点不同，因为它不是以“-est”结尾的，
is.
不是那种形式。
Right.
对。
It's not like tastiest or healthiest.
它不像“tastiest”或“healthiest”。
It's just best.
它就是“best”。
Right.
对。
You're saying that it's the number one.
你说的是它排第一。
So the best milkshake in town like in this dialogue.
所以就像对话里说的，城里最好的奶昔。
Or you say the best soccer player in the world is so and so.
或者你说世界上最好的足球运动员是谁谁谁。
Alright, so this comes from the adjective good.
好的，这来自形容词“good”。
So we have good which is not bad and the best which is the most good, right?
所以有“good”表示不坏，而“best”表示最好，对吧？
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
But you don't say the most good.
但你不说“most good”。
You say the best.
你说“the best”。
He's the best.
他是最好的。
So maybe Ronaldo is one of the best soccer players in the world.
所以也许罗纳尔多是世界上最好的足球运动员之一。
Exactly.
没错。
Alright.
好的。
So now let's take a break.
那么现在我们休息一下。
Let's take a look at everything again and we'll be right back with Fluency Builder.
让我们再看一遍所有内容，然后我们马上回来进行流利度训练。
Oh, dear miss, you are soaked.
哦，亲爱的女士，您全身都湿透了。
Wow, it's really raining heavily outside.
哇，外面雨下得真大。
Yes, it sure is.
是啊，确实如此。
I had to run here from work.
我得从工作的地方跑过来。
I need to rush as I'm on my lunch break.
我得赶紧，因为我在午休时间。
Well, please, why don't you go ahead of me in line?
嗯，请吧，您排在我前面吧？
I'm in no hurry.
我不着急。
Oh, that's so nice of you.
哦，你真是太好了。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
My pleasure, miss.
不客气，女士。
Actually, could you recommend what to eat here?
实际上，你能推荐一下这里吃什么吗？
I've never been here before.
我以前从没来过这里。
Sure.
当然。
Well, the avocado sandwich is delicious and it's the healthiest thing on the menu.
嗯，鳄梨三明治很好吃，而且是菜单上最健康的食物。
Personally, I think the beef salad is the tastiest choice.
就我个人而言，我觉得牛肉沙拉是最好吃的选择。
I usually get that.
我通常点那个。
Also, the milkshakes are the best milkshakes in town.
还有，奶昔是城里最好的奶昔。
Well, thanks for the suggestions.
嗯，谢谢你的建议。
Don't mention it.
不客气。
All right, we're back so now let's take a look at three phrases we picked out on Fluency
好的，我们回来了，现在让我们看看在流利度训练中挑出的三个短语。
Builder.
流利度训练。
Fluency Builder.
So, we have a great phrase here, something that we often hear in conversation, polite
我们这里有一个很棒的短语，是我们在对话中经常听到的，礼貌的
conversations.
对话中。
The older man says, I'm in no hurry.
那位年长的男士说：“我不赶时间。”
Now, what does this mean?
那么，这是什么意思呢？
Does this mean he needs to go somewhere?
这是说他需要去某个地方吗？
No, he says, you know what?
不，他说：“你知道吗？”
I really don't have to go anywhere fast.
我真的不需要急着去任何地方。
That's why he let her, the girl, get in front of him in line at the shop.
这就是为什么他让那个女孩在商店里排在他前面。
All right, so basically it means I can wait.
好的，所以基本上它的意思是我可以等。
I can wait, yeah.
我可以等，是的。
So, if somebody says, oh, I'll be right back.
所以，如果有人对你说：“哦，我马上回来。”
Please wait a moment.
请稍等一下。
You can say, I'm in no hurry.
你可以说：“我不赶时间。”
Take your time.
慢慢来。
Okay, so I'm in no hurry means it's not that important.
好的，所以“我不赶时间”意味着这没那么重要。
I don't have to go fast.
我不需要赶着走。
Right, but if you change the no and you say, I'm in a hurry, then that means that you have
对，但如果你把“不”字改掉，说“我很赶时间”，那就意味着你
to go fast.
得快点走。
Come on, Marco.
快点，马可。
Speed it up.
加快速度。
I'm in a hurry.
我很赶时间。
Okay.
好的。
Yes.
是的。
So, just changing those two words, that gives you a completely different meaning.
所以，仅仅改变这两个词，就带来了完全不同的意思。
And well, the girl, Michelle, she said, oh, that's so nice of you.
而那个女孩，米歇尔，她说：“哦，你真是太好了。”
Thank you very much.
非常感谢你。
And he says, my pleasure.
他说：“这是我的荣幸。”
All right, so this is an alternative to the phrase, you're welcome.
好的，所以这是“不客气”的另一种说法。
This is a very polite way to say you're welcome.
这是一种非常礼貌的表达“不客气”的方式。
And so, when we hear her thank him for something, you know, thank you for letting me go ahead
所以，当我们听到她感谢他做某事时，比如“谢谢你让我排在你前面”，
of you, he says, my pleasure.
他说：“这是我的荣幸。”
This is a great, great phrase for you guys.
这对你们来说是一个非常非常好的短语。
Exactly.
没错。
So, now you have another alternative instead of saying, you're welcome or no problem or
所以，现在你们有了另一种选择，而不是只说“不客气”或“没问题”或
don't mention it.
“别客气”。
Now you have, it's my pleasure.
现在你们有了“这是我的荣幸”。
This is a little bit more formal, but you can use it in any circumstance.
这稍微正式一点，但你可以在任何场合使用它。
That's right.
没错。
And as I said, another option here is the phrase, don't mention it, which means exactly
正如我所说，另一个选择是短语“别客气”，它的意思完全
the same thing.
相同。
You're welcome.
不客气。
That's right.
没错。
So, the older gentleman says, thanks for the suggestions.
所以，那位年长的绅士说：“谢谢你的建议。”
Thanks for your help.
“谢谢你的帮助。”
And what does the young woman say?
那位年轻女士说了什么？
Don't mention it.
“别客气。”
So, this is more colloquial.
所以，这更口语化。
This is a little bit more spoken language.
这更偏向于口语表达。
She's saying, no problem.
她在说：“没问题。”
You're welcome.
“不客气。”
That's right.
没错。
So, you have, you're welcome, no problem, my pleasure, don't mention it.
所以，你们有“不客气”、“没问题”、“我的荣幸”、“别客气”。
All ways of saying the same thing.
都是表达同一意思的方式。
All right.
好的。
So, let's take another listen to our dialogue.
那么，让我们再听一遍我们的对话。
We'll be back in a moment.
我们一会儿就回来。
Oh, dear miss, you are soaked.
哦，亲爱的小姐，你全身都湿透了。
Wow, it's really raining heavily outside.
哇，外面雨下得真大。
Yes, it sure is.
是的，确实如此。
I had to run here from work.
我不得不从工作的地方跑过来。
I need to rush as I'm on my lunch break.
我得赶紧，因为我在午休时间。
Well, please, why don't you go ahead of me in line?
嗯，请吧，不如你排在我前面？
I'm in no hurry.
我不赶时间。
Oh, that's so nice of you.
哦，你真是太好了。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢你。
My pleasure, miss.
这是我的荣幸，小姐。
Actually, could you recommend what to eat here?
实际上，你能推荐这里有什么好吃的吗？
I've never been here before.
我以前从没来过这里。
Sure.
当然。
Well, the avocado sandwich is delicious and it's the healthiest thing on the menu.
嗯，牛油果三明治很好吃，而且是菜单上最健康的。
Personally, I think the beef salad is the tastiest choice.
我个人觉得牛肉沙拉是最好吃的选择。
I usually get that.
我通常点那个。
Also, the milkshakes are the best milkshakes in town.
还有，奶昔是镇上最好喝的奶昔。
Wow, thanks for the suggestions.
哇，谢谢你的建议。
No, don't mention it.
不，别客气。
All right, we're back.
好的，我们回来了。
So, talking about the superlatives, I know it's a complicated subject because grammar-wise,
那么，谈到最高级，我知道这是一个复杂的话题，因为从语法上讲，
it can be a little bit difficult to determine when do you say, for example, beautiful.
比如说，要判断什么时候该用“beautiful”这个词，可能会有点困难。
Do you say more beautiful or do you say beautiful-est?
你是说“more beautiful”还是“beautiful-est”？
You say more beautiful.
你说“more beautiful”。
That's right.
没错。
Well, I don't really have a hard and fast rule for everyone.
嗯，我并没有一个对所有人都适用的硬性规则。
It's one of those things that you learn while you're studying English and you just have
这是你在学习英语过程中需要掌握的东西，你只需要
to remember.
记住它。
Yes, there are some exceptions, but usually you can guide yourself by adjectives that
是的，有些例外情况，但通常你可以根据形容词的
have usually three or more syllables.
音节数来指导自己，一般三个或更多音节的形容词。
You probably have to use most or more.
你可能得用“most”或“more”。
Amazing.
太棒了。
Right, you don't say amazing-est.
对，你不会说“amazing-est”。
Most amazing.
“Most amazing”。
Most amazing or more amazing.
“Most amazing”或“more amazing”。
What about funny?
那“funny”呢？
Funny.
“Funny”。
Often you say funnier or funniest.
通常你会说“funnier”或“funniest”。
Or sad.
或者“sad”。
You can say saddest.
你可以说“saddest”。
All right, so sad, funny, these are one and two syllables, sad, funny, saddest, funniest,
好的，所以“sad”、“funny”这些是一个或两个音节的词，“sad”、“funny”、“saddest”、“funniest”，
you can use this ending.
你可以用这种词尾变化。
But with the words like beautiful or amazing, there are three syllables, they're long, you
但对于像“beautiful”或“amazing”这样的词，它们有三个音节，比较长，你
have to say most amazing, most beautiful.
得说“most amazing”、“most beautiful”。
Yeah, and there are some exceptions to the rule, you may find them, but usually if you
是的，规则也有一些例外，你可能会遇到，但通常如果你
see an adjective that's a little bit long like this, you can just say, you can just
看到一个比较长的形容词，比如这样，你就可以直接
use more for the comparative or most for the superlative.
用“more”表示比较级，或者“most”表示最高级。
All right, so lots of stuff there.
好的，内容挺多的。
I recommend that you guys go check out the dialogue and expansion sentences we have for
我建议你们去看看我们今天准备的对话和扩展句子。
today.
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
All right, we'll see you guys there.
好的，我们那儿见。
Bye.
再见。
Basically we're looking at the phase回去 we talked about, the phase word here.
基本上我们是在看我们之前讨论过的“回去”这个阶段，这里的阶段词。
So the words回來, come back here and then we say back, come back here, come.
所以“回来”这个词，回到这里，然后我们说“back”，“come back here”，“come”。
Right?
对吧？
Okay.
好的。
Bye.
再见。